In nature, there are boundaries. One man spent the last
thirteen years of his life crossing them.
Grizzly Man is a documentary film directed by Werner Herzog.
Follows the story of "Grizzly Man" Timothy Treadwell and what the thirteen summers in a
National Park in Alaska were like in his attempt to protect the grizzly bears.
The film is full of unique images and a look into the spirit
of a man who sacrificed himself for nature.
Self - Actor, Close Friend, played by Warren Queeney.
Self - Pilot, Former Rodeo Rider, played by Willy Fulton.
Self - Egli Air Haul, played by Sam Egli.
Self - Ecologist, played by Marnie Gaede.
Self - Ecologist, played by Marc Gaede.
Self - Bear Biologist, played by Larry Van Daele.
Grizzly Man is a 2005 American documentary film
written and directed by Werner Herzog.
It chronicles the life and death of bear enthusiast and conservationist Timothy
Treadwell and his girlfriend Amie Huguenard at Katmai National Park, Alaska.
The film includes some of Treadwell's own footage of his interactions with brown bears before 2003, and of interviews with
people who knew or were involved with Treadwell, in addition to professionals who deal with wild bears.
Treadwell and Huguenard, both from New York, had bonded over their common passion for bears and
animal conservation, and she would occasionally accompany him on his trips to the park.
Having stayed past the summer season one year, the pair were attacked
and killed in the park by a bear on October 5, 2003.
The couple's remains were discovered by a patrolling pilot, and an audio recording of the attack was found
among the remains; the bear was later tracked down and killed by the pilot's rescue team.
The film was co-produced by Discovery Docs and Lions Gate Entertainment.
The film's soundtrack was composed by Richard Thompson.
It received widespread acclaim from critics and is now considered to be
among the best films of the 2000s and of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of self-abandonment, life and death,
unsociability, grizzly bear, human animal relationship.